[Starting today,]
从今天开始
[I will be temporarily stepping in]
我就暂代
[as the general manager.]
总经理一职
Let me introduce to you:
我给大家介绍一下
this is Yuan Lang.
元朗
And Ren Tingting.
任亭亭
They are our new account managers.
客户经理
Come on,
来
let's get to know each other.
相互认识一下
Hello everyone,
大家好
I'm Ren Tingting.
我是任亭亭
Hi guys, I'm Yuan Lang.
大家好我是元朗
Let's assign
分配一下
the tasks at hand.
下边的工作吧
First up,
第一件呢
Xu Li,
许力
you go and
你找那个
reconcile deposit account with Yuhui
小唐勾兑一下
from Shunjue for the next quarter.
舜决下季度的存款
Come again, Jing?
谁姐
You heard me right.
对
The "Yuhui."
就是那个小唐
The "Yuhui?"
那个小唐
[A reminder for you.]
我跟你说啊
[Maintain a professional distance.]
不要掺杂私人感情
[Performance is what matters,]
业绩第一
got it?
明白吗
Got it.
好
Li Xiang,
李想
follow up the progress
城南那家
on the loan from the
外贸企业的贷款
foreign trade company in Chengnan district.
你继续跟进一下
Yes, Jing.
好的经理
Xiaoning, sweetie,
我们筱柠
regarding the domestic LC for that
前两天那个
microenterprise we met a few days ago,
小微企业的国内信用证
they felt our quote
他们嫌我们的报价
was too high.
太高了
[They'd like to apply for a discount.]
然后想申请一下优惠
[You go and check if there's]
你看还有没有一个
any room for a discount
优惠的空间
that we can offer them?
可以给到他们
Sure, Jing.
好的静姐
Ms. Rao,
饶总
regarding the LC,
信用证的事
I've handled a few cases with the manager
前段时间我在支行
at another branch recently.
跟着经理做过几笔
Could you please also let me in on this?
要不要考虑一下我
I thought
我本来说
you two just joined the team,
你们俩刚到我们部门吧
and will take some time to get familiar
先熟悉一下
with the business within section one.
我们拓展一部
Since you're so
那既然这么
ambitious,
有上进心的话
you can team up with Xiaoning
你就跟筱柠
on that project.
做那个项目吧
Alright.
好
Sir, you're something.
大伯真可以啊
Not paying back the principal,
不还本金
not paying interest,
不付利息
and refusing to negotiate.
也不肯协商
You're not shy of
更不怕把这个老赖
being a deadbeat at all.
做到底了呀
I think you're just
要我看您就是
taking a chance,
抱着侥幸心理
thinking that the bank
觉得我们银行
won't bother with this
不会把你这一点小钱
small amount of money
放在眼里
and we won't just sue you.
也不会去直接起诉你
Please keep in mind,
但是你也别忘了
the bank
我们银行
isn't exactly a soft target.
其实也不是冤大头
In addition to filing a lawsuit,
除了起诉之外
the court can also initiate a
法院还可以强制拍卖
forced auction to compensate our losses.
来追回我们的损失
I just took a look around
我刚才看着
at your
咱们这些
aquaculture facilities.
水产基地
And they actually look quite profitable.
做得还挺像模像样
If we really put them up for auction,
要真是拿出去拍卖呀
we might get a
说不定能有一个
juicy compensation out of them.
好的价格
If you fail to repay,
你要是不还钱
we could simply
我们就可以直接
sell all these
强行把你这些东西
properties off.
给卖掉
Alternatively,
或者是通过
through the right of recovery,
追索权的方式
we can reclaim those loans
从你的第三方财产里面
from your third-party properties.
追索出来那些贷款
I hope you'll consider my advice.
听我一句劝
no matter which route you choose,
不管是哪种方式
It's not in your best interest.
都不适合你
It will become challenging for you
你以后想要
to pursue fish farming business
踏踏实实地去养鱼
in the future.
都不容易了
So think it through.
所以想明白一点
Hey, honey,
喂 老婆
I am just off from
我刚从
Yuheng's friend's company.
老纪朋友的公司出来
The account manager here
他这边的客户经理
is taking his parent
要带家里的老人
to Beijing for medical treatment.
去北京看病
He asked me to fill in for two months.
找我替俩月
You know what?
我跟你说
The pay here is really generous!
工资开得可大方了
How's going with you?
你呢
Ms. Manager.
饶总
How did your first day go?
头一天上岗还顺利吧
By the way,
对了
You only had a bun for breakfast, right?
你早上只吃了个包子
You must be starving by now.
这会儿应该饿了吧
I'll bring you some cheese pancakes.
我给你送点芝士饼去
No, I'm really not hungry.
行了我不饿
I'm good.
不吃
I don't want them.
不要
Stop nagging.
你别叨叨了
I'm in the middle of
我跟那个筱柠
a discussion with Xiaoning.
在说工作的事呢
Just hold on a sec.
等会儿
[Don't order food delivery.]
你别点外卖
[I'll bring you lunch instead.]
我给你送饭去
[I'll whip up some]
做个
[braised pork chops with scallions,]
葱烧猪排
minced meat with eggplant,
肉末茄子
and fried Hangzhou cabbage.
再炒个杭白菜
[I'll make sure it's light.]
我尽量做清淡一点
I promise it will be nutritious
保证你营养均衡的同时
and won't add any extra pounds.
还不长肥膘
Fine, fine.
行 行
Got it.
我知道了
Do as you please.
随你啊
That's so sweet!
好甜呀
What's sweet about him?
还甜呀
Guess what he
你猜他打电话
told me on the phone?
跟我说什么
He told me not to burn myself out.
说让我别累着
Is that even realistic?
可能吗
You know, in just a few months,
你说再过几个月
my belly will start to show!
我这肚子就显怀了
I have to give birth soon.
我就得去生孩子
Before that happens,
我在生孩子之前
I need to deliver some results.
我不得做出点业绩呀
Otherwise,
要不我这个
I could easily lose this
代经理的位置
acting manager position.
分分钟就失守了
Marriage and motherhood are
婚育是职场女性
the biggest hurdles for career women.
最大的障碍
I'm really feeling this
我现在是切身地
firsthand now.
体会到了
It's challenging.
难哪
Take it easy,
不用这么焦虑啊
Jing.
姐
With your skills,
你放心以你的能力
you'll definitely drop the "acting"
一定在休产假之前
before you go on maternity leave.
把这个代字给去掉
Besides,
再说
aren't we all here for you,
不是还有我们这些
your right-hand and left-hand support?
左膀右臂在吗
What's there to worry about?
你担心什么呀
That's a good point.
也是
I hope so too.
但愿吧
About the letter of credit,
这个信用证的事呢
I need to discuss it with you.
我得跟你商量一下
If we can't compete with
如果我们争不过
the state-owned banks,
国有银行的话
how about we
要不
explore a different cooperation approach?
我们换一种合作方式吧
Mr. Ji,
纪总
he really agreed
他真的同意
to start repaying the interest next week?
下周起偿还利息啊
How did you pull that off?
你是怎么做到的
Every time we approached him before,
我们之前每次找他
he wouldn't say a word.
他都一声不吭
It left us talking until we were hoarse,
搞得我俩说得口干舌燥
and it was still all in vain.
也不顶用
You know, before I came here,
其实我来之前呀
I did some digging into his background.
就做了他的调查
He's a local.
这个人是本地人
He's very attached to his hometown.
安土重迁
Outside of the village,
在村子之外
he doesn't own any fixed assets.
没有任何的固定资产
So when dealing with someone like him,
所以对付这种人
threatening him with being
讲你跟他讲
labeled on the discredit list
失信人员
and restricting his spending,
限制他高额消费
like banning him from flying,
不能坐飞机那套
is completely ineffective.
根本没用
What he truly values
他最在意的东西
is the key point for our negotiation.
才是我们谈判的切入点
Mr. Ji, your acumen is remarkable.
纪总您业务能力真强
You not only excel in negotiation,
还懂谈判
but you also have a grasp of psychology.
还研究心理学
With you leading our branch,
咱们支行啊
those bad debts now
有了纪总
have a chance of recovery.
那几笔烂账是有救了
After a busy morning with me,
跟着我忙一上午
you've all put in a lot of effort.
也都辛苦了
After we get back to the office,
咱们回单位之后
let's order some coffee.
点点咖啡喝
It's on me.
我来请客
Thanks, Mr. Ji.
谢谢纪总
Let's go.
走
Coffee?
咖啡
Why did you get so much coffee?
你怎么买这么多咖啡啊
[Just wanted to show you that I miss you.]
让你知道我挂念你呢
You bought all these
那你买这么多
so I could bribe my colleagues?
是想让我贿赂同事啊
[I am the one bribing them here.]
是我想贿赂他们
[While I'm not around,]
我不在你眼前的日子
[I'd like them to say]
让他们在你面前
[something nice about me.]
多说几句我的好话
They still haven't returned yet?
都还没回来呢
Have some coffee.
喝咖啡
Wow, that's a lot of coffee!
这么多咖啡啊
This, um...
这 这
From a client?
客户送的
I wouldn't accept coffee from a client.
我哪敢收客户的咖啡呀
I'll help myself then.
那我自己拿了
It's from our former boss.
前老板送的
The boss!
领导
I knew the boss
我就知道领导
still thinks of us.
还惦记着我们呢
In comparison with him,
这一对比
Fanggang is
小赵哥
so scrimping.
抠搜的
He made me deliver
天天使唤我
lunch to Jing every day
给静姐送餐
and never bought me dinner.
也不请我吃顿饭
The boss is truly a great guy.
领导真是好男人
Even while busy with work,
你这工作时候
he still has you on his mind.
还惦记着你
Thanks to you, we've got coffee as well.
还爱屋及乌
Your relationship
你们这感情
is sweeter than coffee itself.
比咖啡都香
You are the sweet one here, aren't you?
你怎么这么会说话
I might spill the beans to Fanggang.
你小心我告诉小赵哥
You guys are back. Have some coffee!
回来啦喝咖啡
Wow, it's a wonderful day today!
今天什么好日子啊
We've got coffee to savor.
还有咖啡喝
It's from the former boss.
前老板送的
Come on, come on!
来 来 来
Let's share.
分一分 分一分
Thank you!
谢谢
Thanks! We'll take this one.
谢谢 那我俩就拿这个
Here, here.
来 来 来
Grab this.
拿这个 拿这个
This coffee smells absolutely divine!
这咖啡真香
When it comes to experience,
论资历
we're just as qualified as Tu Xiaoning.
咱们和涂筱柠不相上下
Is it really appropriate for Ms. Rao
饶总让她来带我们
to have her lead us?
说不过去吧
She is quite capable, though.
小涂姐能力挺强的
She's someone who has made her way with
她可是打入
Weiji Company.
惟纪公司内部的人
Working with her,
跟着她
you're bound to gain valuable insights.
一定能学到东西的
You're so naive.
你太单纯啦
Whether she was the one who secured
惟纪公司
that project is still up for debate.
是不是她打入的不一定
Isn't the last manager of section one,
之前拓展一部的纪总
Mr. Ji, her boyfriend? Given his position.
不是她男朋友吗
It's only natural that she would
那想给她一点
receive some dividends and credit
分红和业绩
from him.
不要太正常
Now Mr. Ji
现在纪总
has been reassigned to the countryside
因为他俩的事
because of their relationship.
被调到乡下去
She's likely
她指定
not going to achieve much.
什么也做不成
You guys are having a chat, huh?
聊天呢
Xiao...
小
Xiaoning...
小 小涂姐
Sipping on someone's coffee,
喝着别人的咖啡
let's not gossip about his girlfriend.
就别议论他女朋友了吧
This afternoon,
我下午呢
I'll meet a client regarding the LC.
要去谈信用证的事
Yuan Lang,
元朗
if you're free,
你有时间的话
come along with me.
就跟着一起去
Absolutely.
有
Shentong Bank is just across the street.
对面就是申同银行了
You set the meeting in here.
你把客户约到这儿
Aren't you concerned that the client
就不怕客户
might go straight to the other side?
直奔着门口去对面了吗
I'm not meeting with a client,
我约的不是客户
but an account manager from Shentong.
是申同的客户经理
[Regarding the letter of credit,]
信用证的事
[I've already]
我跟
[discussed it with the global department.]
国际部沟通过了
Even if we
即使我们
waive the fees,
减免手续费
our quotation
我们的价格
still couldn't possibly be more
也不可能
competitive than what Shentong,
比国有银行的申同
a state-owned bank offers.
更有优势
One of the main reasons companies
企业选择信用证
opt for letters of credit
目的之一
is to effectively manage cash flow
就是为了管理现金流
and control their overall expenses.
控制企业成本支出
Since we can't
我们既然
help them save money,
不能帮他们省钱
it's natural they'll seek other options.
他们当然会去找别人
But we can't just
那也不能就这么
offer Shentong our clients
这么直接把客户
for free, right?
送出去吧
Who said I want to give them away?
谁说我要送出去了
We're aiming for collaboration here.
我们是要合作
I've already discussed it with Ms. Rao.
我跟饶总商量过了
By partnering with Shentong,
跟申同合作
we can exchange clients with them.
我们把客户置换给他们
This way, we can help clients
既可以帮客户
save a significant amount of money,
省一大笔财务费
and also do Shentong
又可以做个顺水人情
a favor.
给申同
They would definitely appreciate
他们当然愿意
swapping companies
把跟国有银行
that have difficulty dealing
不好对接的企业
with state-owned banks.
置换给我们
This creates a win-win situation,
这叫各取所需
a positive cycle for all involved.
良性循环
Hello!
你好
You must be Mr. Qiao.
乔经理是吧
Yes, nice to meet you.
对 你好
I'm Qiao Mu.
我是乔穆
It's a pleasure working with you.
很高兴有机会合作
Nice to meet you, I'm Tu Xiaoning.
你好 涂筱柠
Please, take a seat.
请坐
This is my colleague, Yuan Lang.
这是我的同事元朗
Nice to meet you!
你好
We've previously discussed that
那个要申请
small and microenterprise that is
信用贷的小微企业
applying for credit loans.
之前我们也沟通过了
You're likely aware of their situation.
它的情况您也都知道了
What can you
不知道
tell us about the company
您要置换给我们的企业
you're looking to swap with us?
是什么情况呢
Here's the situation:
是这样的
the client specializes in bedding products.
客户是做床上用品的
Their facilities have been mortgaged to us.
厂房已经抵押给我们了
Now they want to use the
现在想用厂房
vacant land behind the facilities
后面的一块空地
as collateral to secure a loan.
做抵押申请贷款
However, Shentong can't provide them
但是我们申同
with the interest rate they're seeking.
给不了他们想要的利率
Have you had a chance to review
你们有看过
their
他们的
tax documentation?
纳税系统吗
Absolutely.
当然
Their company adheres to
他们公司在财务上
proper financial protocols.
是很正规的
If Mr. Qiao feels
如果乔经理觉得
there are no issues, we can start with
没问题的话
gathering the necessary documents
我们可以先收集资料
and submit them for approval.
上报审批
We can apply for credit and the
边申请授信
associated benefits simultaneously.
边向银行申报优惠
Once we receive the credit authorization,
等授信授权了以后呢
if they find the interest rate acceptable,
如果企业觉得利率合适
they can proceed to withdrawal.
再提款
How about that?
您觉得怎么样
[That sounds good to me.]
没问题
[I'll also prioritize the processing]
那信用证那边
[of the letter of credit.]
我也会抓紧处理
Perfect!
好
I'll send you their tax documents
尽快把企业税票
as soon as possible.
给你送过来
Ms. Tu,
涂小姐
thank you for referring the client to me.
谢谢你把客户让给我
It really helped me
让我完成了一项
meet a target.
任务指标
No need to mention it.
别客气
Our quotation
我们的价格
is indeed not competitive.
确实没有优势
By doing this,
那这样做的话
we can help the client
可以帮
save a substantial amount on expenses.
企业省一大笔的支出
At the end of the day,
说到底
it's all about putting their needs first.
都是为了客户着想
We're just
我们也算是
having each other's backs.
彼此成就
Exactly!
好
Let's aim for more collaboration soon.
那咱们以后多多合作
[Later, as we were leaving,]
后来我们回去的时候呢
Yuan Lang even apologized to me,
元朗还跟我道歉来着
saying he
说
shouldn't have spoken about me that way.
他不应该那么说我
Honestly, I'm quite capable.
其实我还是挺厉害的
I'm not the type to rely on men.
不是靠男人的那种人
So how did you respond?
那后来你怎么说呀
I told him,
我跟他说
of course,
那当然了
with Mr. Ji,
我跟我们家纪先生
we each stand on our own.
分则各自为王
But together, we're truly unmatched.
合则天下无双
Did you really tell him that?
真这么说的
Of course not!
当然没有了
If I said that,
我要这么说
that would be way too cheesy!
也太中二了吧
But honestly, that's how I feel inside.
不过我心里是这么想的
I feel the same way.
我也是这么想的
In my heart, you are the
在我心里你是全世界
most exceptional person in the world.
最优秀的人
They just don't see your true worth.
是他们有眼不识泰山了
Today, that
今天那个
account manager from Shentong
申同的客户经理
also complimented me like that.
也是这么夸我的
His name is
叫
Qiao Mu.
乔穆
Do you know him?
你认识不
He's said to be one of
据说是申同的
the four cutest men at Shentong.
四大美男之一
The four cutest men, huh?
四大美男啊
Is he cuter than me?
有我帅吗
Just
就
a little bit, I suppose.
帅那么一点点吧
A little bit, huh?
一点点啊
A little bit!
一点点
Do you know how much I
你知道这一天
missed you today?
我多想你吗
Don't worry,
放心吧
I'll definitely get reassigned back soon.
我一定会尽快调回来的
[Xiaoning,]
筱柠
[I'm here to drop off the documents.]
我来送材料
[I'm waiting for you]
在你们楼下的
[in the parking lot downstairs.]
停车场等你
Just hold on a moment.
你等我一下
I'll be right there.
我这就下来
Qiao Mu!
乔穆
Try this coffee
新开咖啡店的咖啡
from the new café.
尝尝看
Thank you so much.
这多不好意思啊
It's very kind of you.
让你破费了
Mr. Ji?
纪总
What brings you here?
你怎么来这儿了
I need to finish some transfer paperwork.
有些调职手续要补办
And who is this?
这位是
Hello, Mr. Ji.
纪总你好
I'm Qiao Mu from Shentong.
申同乔穆
We've got similar tastes.
品味很相同啊
This coffee is from the new café.
新开的咖啡店
I just bought some for you yesterday.
昨天刚给你买了
How was it?
味道怎么样
It's quite good.
还不错
Mr. Ji, would you like to give it a try?
纪总要不要尝尝看
I just drove over and I'm a bit tired.
正好开车过来有点困了
Thank you!
谢谢啊
I've organized all the files
信用证所需要的材料
needed for the LC based on
都按照你们
your global department's requirements.
国际部的要求整理好了
I'll send you the
稍后我会把
scanned copies of the
国内信用证
submission letter of
交单面函的扫描件
the domestic letter of credit shortly.
先发给你
Then I'll send the
回头再把
originals to you afterwards.
原件再寄过来
Thank you!
辛苦你了
OK.
行
No problem at all.
那我就不打扰了
I'll see you around.
先走一步
Thanks!
辛苦
So this is one of the legendary
这就是传说中的
four cutest men of Shentong, huh?
申同四大美男
Zhao Fanggang would be considered
老赵去了他们行里
a top-tier cute guy at their bank.
都是顶级美男了
Mr. Ji, usually,
纪总平时上班
you don't wear the ring at work.
不是不戴戒指吗
Why are you wearing it today?
今天怎么戴上了
I'm doing it on purpose.
特意的呀
It's important to show that I'm taken,
已婚男士在外工作的
especially in a professional setting.
自我操守
Was that gesture you just made
你刚才这个动作
a bit too obvious?
是不是有点太明显了
Ignore it.
忽略不计
Whose car is that?
开的谁的车呀
It's yours.
你的
Mine?
我的
It's a gift.
送你的
I just received a bonus.
我刚拿了一笔奖金
How do you justify such lavish spending?
你怎么乱花钱呀
It's not lavish at all.
什么叫乱花钱
You really need a car.
你现在需要一辆车的
And I know
而且这个车的经销商
the dealer.
我认识
That's why I chose this model.
所以选了这款
I've placed your vehicle registration
行驶证驾驶证
and driver's license in the compartment.
放在了储物箱里
I've also prepared tissues
日常需要的湿巾和纸巾
for your daily use.
也都已经备好了
Additionally,
另外
the dashcam
行车记录仪
has been tested and is ready to go.
已经都测试好了
You don't need to worry about anything.
放心开
[Giving me such an expensive gift]
突然送我
[all of a sudden,]
这么贵重的礼物
[is he planning to propose?]
不会是想跟我求婚吧
Why are you suddenly giving me
你为什么突然要送我
such an expensive gift?
这么贵重的礼物啊
In the past,
以前的时候
we could commute together.
上班下班咱们都能一起
Even in bad weather,
就算是刮风下雨
we wouldn't have to worry.
也不用害怕
Now that I work in Nanan County,
现在去了南安县
if the weather turns bad one day,
万一哪天天气不好
or if you're working late,
或者是你加班太晚了
you driving it will give me peace of mind.
有辆车我能放心一点
That's it?
就这些啊
Well then,
那
Isn't this a bit too pricey?
那这也太贵了吧
Isn't it a bit too showy?
会不会太高调了
Not at all.
一点不张扬也不高调
Besides,
再说了
you're now
你现在可是
an account manager for Dairui.
代瑞的客户经理
You're a veteran on the team.
是部门的大前辈了
This car is perfectly suited for you.
这车一点都不高调
It's just right.
正适合
It's great.
挺好的
What do you mean by "great"?
什么挺好的
I think Mr. Ji's fortune
我觉得纪经理的运气
is great as well.
也挺好的呀
You got here just in time to see Qiao Mu.
刚过来就遇见乔穆了
You gave me such a
你当着他的面
generous gift right in front of him.
送我一这么大的礼物
I bet in a few days,
那估计过几天
Mr. Ji will earn
纪经理是一个
the title of
宠妻狂魔的称号
"Wife Spoiling Maniac."
就传开了
Looks like this
那看来这次
gift really works on you.
是个有效送礼
Absolutely.
当然
I love it.
我喜欢
Thank you.
谢谢你啊
What matters most is that you like it.
你喜欢最重要
Jing!
静姐
Mr. Ji!
纪总
Long time no see!
好久不见啊
Good to see you again.
好久不见
What brings you here
不是大中午的
in the middle of the day?
你在我们楼下干吗呢
Having a heart-to-heart with Xiaoning?
找小涂谈心啊
No problem.
没事
Don't be shy.
别害羞
You kids have fun.
你俩好好谈
I'm going upstairs now.
我先上去
I'll be there soon, Jing.
我马上上去姐
OK.
好
See ya!
走啦
During work hours,
上班时间
out on a date,
出来约会
caught by the boss,
被上司抓包
that's just too awkward!
这也太尴尬了吧
I can't help you with that.
这我可帮不了你
You'll have to face it alone.
得独自面对
You
你
park the car in the underground parking.
把车给我停地库去
Leave the keys to Ling Weiyi.
钥匙给凌惟依
Yes, Ms. Tu.
好的涂总
I'm off then.
我走了
OK.
去吧
Jing,
静姐
didn't you go to the newly built
你下午不是去
private high school this afternoon
新建成那个私立高中
to discuss payroll?
谈代发工资了吗
What's up?
怎么了
Was it not going well?
不太顺利啊
That project isn't under our jurisdiction.
那个项目啊
Some else took it.
不在咱们片区被人切了
Also,
但是呢
the contract hasn't been signed yet.
还没有过合同
I'll think of another way.
我再想想办法吧
But I feel like
可是我觉得
the hope is slim.
希望不大
We've got Shentong onboard.
申同那边已经谈好了
I'll try to
我争取今天呢
go through the files and agreements
把资料跟协议
today.
都过一遍
And get them signed by tomorrow.
争取明天签字走流程了
If that's the case,
这样的话
our performance for this month
我们这个月的业绩
will be secured.
也算是有着落了
Jing,
静姐
don't worry.
你别太焦虑了
Li Xiang and Xu Li,
李想哥跟许力哥
their projects
他们那几个客户
are in the process.
都正常进行中呢
Tingting and Yuan Lang
亭亭跟元朗
are quite enthusiastic about
拉存款的积极性
attracting deposits.
也挺高的
Let's both put in more effort
咱们俩再努努力
and aim to develop one or two
争取开辟一两个
new clients.
新的客户
Before you give birth,
在你生孩子之前
we'll definitely achieve
肯定能做出一个
some excellent results
非常好的成绩
to show the higher-ups.
让领导看看
If we do that, they will
这样的话他们就会
have more confidence in you.
更信任你
Honestly,
说实话
I've been feeling quite anxious lately.
我最近确实挺焦虑的
Don't you think I look thinner now
你觉没觉得我怀孕以后
that I'm pregnant?
好像比怀孕之前还瘦了
From the look of your face,
反正看脸
it's pretty noticeable.
挺明显的
Right?
是吧
You know, when I was an account manager,
你说以前我做客户经理
I had a lot of work,
工作也挺多
and the pressure was intense,
压力也挺大
right?
对吧
[But after work,]
但是我下了班呢
[I would find a place to have a drink,]
我找个地方我喝两杯
[and dance a bit.]
我蹦几下
That would help relieve the stress.
那压力也就释放出去了
But ever since I got conceived,
但是自从有了孩子
that Zhao guy
姓赵的那个
won't let me drink any booze,
这不让我碰
or dance.
那不让我摸
I really feel like...
我真的是
Fanggang made it clear.
小赵哥真说了
He instructed me
他交代好了
not to let you drink coffee or tea.
不让你喝咖啡跟茶
He asked me to keep an eye on you.
让我看着你
He's already given you instructions?
都嘱咐到你那儿了
He's reaching out to my turf now?
都管到我的地界上来了
This is for your own good.
这也是为了你好
Fine.
行
You know, when I get home,
你说我回到家之后
I would just lie in bed
我说那我躺床上
and play some mobile games.
打两把游戏吧
That can help relieve some stress.
也能解解压
Let off some steam.
释放下压力
But he won't even let me play games.
他游戏都不让我打
Guess what the reason is?
你猜理由是什么
He's afraid my teammates might suck
他怕队友坑了我
and that would affect my mood.
说影响我的心情
Then I just let it all out on him.
完了我就冲他发火啊
I argue with him,
我就跟他吵架
but he doesn't even respond.
但是他连嘴都不还
Whatever I say,
我说什么
he just takes it all in.
他都照单全收
So it makes me seem like
所以显得我这个人
I have a really bad temper now.
现在脾气特别的暴躁
Right now,
我现在这个
with the rise of pregnancy hormones,
孕期激素的上升
combined with the pressure from work,
叠加工作的压力
I feel like
我整个人我觉得
I'm about to explode.
我就要爆炸了
I really can't
我真的是已经
hold it in anymore.
憋得都不行了
Xiaoning,
筱柠
I beg you,
求求你了
let me have a sip of coffee.
让我喝一口咖啡
You and Mr. Ji are now
你跟纪总现在
in the best phase.
是最好的阶段
You're both still deeply in love.
你们现在还在热恋期
This step we're taking
我们这一步啊
is indeed quite a leap.
真的是跨得有点大
It's a bit challenging to adapt.
适应起来有点难
Fanggang
小赵哥呢
suddenly became a husband.
他突然就成了人夫
[And then,]
然后呢
[suddenly became a soon-to-be dad.]
又突然成了准爸爸
Living cautiously,
小心翼翼地生活
afraid of upsetting you.
生怕你不高兴
Honestly, there's nothing wrong with that.
其实也没什么错
Right?
是吧
Yes.
是
So,
那
Jing,
静姐
I think,
你现在呢
without bad habits,
在不伤害自己的前提下
you find yourself reminiscing
经常怀念起
about the good old days
以前的日子呢
and wanting to find an outlet
想找一个发泄口
is perfectly understandable.
更没有错了
You do?
是吧
So,
所以
I think
我觉得
maybe the problem lies in
可能是你们俩的沟通
your communication.
出现了问题
[If fighting doesn't solve anything,]
如果吵架解决不了问题
then why not
那要不要尝试
try something else?
换一种方式啊
You're just a kid
你个小丫头片子
who isn't even married yet,
还没结婚
and you're giving me advice?
在这儿装前辈指导我呢
Do you want to hear it or not?
那你听不听呀
Tell me.
快给我讲讲
I'm done.
吃完了
Looks like you really enjoyed
看来今天的菜
the food today.
很合胃口啊
Very much so.
特别合胃口
I think after this,
感觉吃完之后
I'll gain three kilos tomorrow.
明天肯定能胖三斤
It's okay.
没事
After you've given birth, I will do
等你生完我陪你做
the postpartum exercise with you.
产后运动
I'll go get the folic acid for you.
我给你拿叶酸
No need.
不用拿了
I took it on time
按时按点
and in sufficient amounts.
足量补充
You
你
are suddenly so initiative,
突然这么自觉
I'm not really used to it.
我怎么还有点不习惯呢
I'm not suddenly initiative.
我哪是突然自觉
I'm not a child
你说我都这么大的人了
[and I'm aware that]
我也知道自己
[I'm pregnant,]
是一个孕妇
of course
那我能不
I'll take good care of myself.
好好照顾自己吗
I was always arguing with you
那之前跟你抬杠
because
还不是因为
you kept controlling me!
你老管着我
But,
但是
it was just bickering,
吵归吵
I still listened to you every time,
是不是最后
didn't I?
每次都听你的了
So that means
那说明我说得
I was making some sense.
还是有点道理的嘛
Not just some sense,
那岂止是有一点道理
you were completely right!
那是相当有道理
Let me tell you again.
我再跟你说一下
Today,
今天
I had
鱼 虾 芦笋
some fish, some shrimps and the asparagus.
都吃了吧
I also had the bird's nest soup
下午四点钟的时候
at four in the afternoon.
我把那个燕窝又给吃了
[And before getting off work,]
下班之前呢
[I also finished the dried fruit]
我把你给我准备的干果
you prepared for me.
也吃完了
My husband has put his heart and soul
你说我的老公
into everything for me,
为我尽心尽力
[always worrying about me.]
操碎了心
How could I not cooperate,
我能不配合吗
right?
是不是
Now,
现在呢
are you satisfied?
满意吗
Very mush so!
满意极了
I'll give you a little star!
给你盖个小红花
However, if you can agree
但是如果你今天
to something now,
要是能答应我一件事呢
I promise I will never
我保证以后
argue with you anymore.
更不跟你抬杠了
Okay,
好
let me hear it.
说来听听
Look,
你看啊
it's still
今天这个
quite early
时间尚早
and the evening is just right,
夜色正好
shouldn't we go out
我们是不是应该出去
and have some fun?
开心一下
Where to?
去哪儿啊
To an
去一个
old place
老地方
and revisit our memories.
找找我们的回忆
Honey,
老婆
slow down.
你走慢一点
What did you say? I can't hear you!
你说什么我听不见
Don't yell so loudly.
别这么大声喊
What's wrong with being loud?
不是大声怎么了
It's not like being,
这大声
being loud
大声说话
can hurt the baby?
还能把孩子说没了
Knock on wood!
呸 呸 呸
Quick!
快 快 快
Knock on wood.
打木头
One,
一
two,
二
three.
三
So superstitious!
迷信
Manager,
经理
I'd like to place an order.
点单
I'll keep it down.
我小点声
Hi, there.
服务员
Hello, Sir,
你好先生
is there anything I can do for you?
有什么可以帮您吗
Could you change the music
咱这个音乐
to some piano songs?
能不能换成钢琴曲啊
My heart can't take
这动次打次的
this pounding beat.
我这心脏受不了
[I'm sorry, Sir.]
不好意思啊先生
The customers are here
咱们这儿的客人
to dance.
都是来蹦迪的
If we switch to piano music,
要是调成钢琴曲的话
they won't be able to dance anymore.
就蹦不起来了呀
Yeah, don't listen to him.
对不用听他的
We'll order.
点单
Okay.
好的
I'll keep it down.
我小点声
I'm telling you,
我跟你讲
with this rhythm,
就是这个节奏
this beat,
这个律动
our child will be born a
我们孩子生下来
rhythm master!
就是一个节奏大师
Give me a break.
你可拉倒吧
Honey,
老公
haven't you been worried about
你不是一直害怕
me developing antepartum depression?
我得那个孕期抑郁症吗
If you don't want me to
你要是不想
develop antepartum depression,
让我有孕期抑郁症
then don't ruin my mood
你今天晚上
tonight.
就别坏了我的心情
I promise you,
我向你保证
If I even feel
我身体
the tiniest bit unwell,
但凡有一丁点不舒服
we'll go home immediately,
咱们就立马回家
okay?
行吗
Okay?
行不行
Slowly.
你慢点晃
I'll be slow.
我慢点晃
This is my favorite song.
我最喜欢的曲子
C'mon, honey!
快老公
Since I can't dance now,
我现在不能去跳
you go dance for me!
你帮我跳
Honey,
老公
Honey.
媳妇
You fell asleep?
睡着了
It's nonalcoholic.
没有酒精的
There's not even ice in it.
连冰块都没放
Honey,
老公
let's go home.
我们回家吧
It's just past 9.
这才九点多
It's not everyday that we go out.
好不容易出来一趟
You go have fun.
你玩尽兴
I haven't been here
这个地方吧
for a long time.
我好长时间没来了
Actually, after coming here today,
今天这么一来我觉得
I find it quite boring.
也挺无聊的
Let's go home.
我们回家吧
Okay.
好
You tricked and coaxed me
你这连哄带骗的
into going to the bar,
把我领去酒吧
and now you're leaving so soon.
中途又撤出来
Why?
到底为什么
Is it you finding it boring?
觉得无聊
It shouldn't be.
不应该吧
Or that you're afraid
还是
I'll scold you?
怕我说你
I think,
我觉得
it must have been hard for you.
辛苦你了
You didn't even drink anything,
像夜店这么吵的地方
if it weren't because
你又没有喝酒
you were too tired,
如果不是因为
how could you have fallen asleep
太累的话
in such a noisy nightclub?
怎么可能睡过去
I'm
我
probably just not very into
可能就是对这种地方
this kind of places.
不太有感觉
You know that.
你也知道
I'm a mellow person.
我这个人比较平和
This pregnancy
怀孕这件事呢
was a surprise
对于你对于我
for both of us.
都来得太突然了
So lately
所以最近呢
I've been trying to
我也在适应
get used to this new role of being a mom,
当妈妈这个新的身份
our new life together.
我们新的生活
But you know sometimes
但是你知道就有时候
I can be hormonal,
激素不平稳
so I might take out some of
所以难免会有一些情绪
my emotions on you.
发泄到你身上
I'm very sorry.
所以对不起啊
It really hasn't been
不过你确实
easy for you.
也挺不容易的
I don't have my parents anymore, so you've
我爸妈走得早
asked your parents to look after me.
你就让你爸妈照顾我
And then
完了呢
you still take care of
你一天
me and the baby everyday,
还要照顾我跟孩子
preparing every single meal
一日三餐营养餐
for me.
顿顿不落
You also took on
还把所有的家务活
all the household chores.
都揽到了自己的身上
You even have to wait for me
就连加班呢
to fall asleep first
也要等我睡着以后
when you have to work overtime.
才能工作
So today
所以我今天
I really want to tell you that,
特别想跟你讲
thank you.
辛苦你了
Is it really necessary
就这件事啊
to make a big deal out of this?
至于吗
If I can't even do this,
我这都做不好
why would I get married?
还为啥结婚啊
You
你这个人啊
have been free for more than thirty years.
自由自在了三十来年
The burden
婚姻
of marriage and children
和孩子两道枷锁
falling on your shoulder at the same time,
一起扣下来
it wouldn't be easy for anyone.
搁谁谁不会难受
I've decided,
我都想好了
I'll take you out
以后
once a week from now on.
每周出去陪你玩一天
But you have to promise me
但是你得答应我
not to look at the handsome men.
不准看黄毛帅哥
I wasn't looking.
我刚才没看
Just this once.
仅此一次
Never again.
下不为例
Plus, are those men
再说那黄毛帅哥
really prettier than your husband?
有你老公耐看啊
Are they
有你老公
more charming, more elegant
风度翩翩英俊潇洒
and more mature than your husband?
成熟稳重啊
I really wasn't looking.
我真没看
Why couldn't you believe me?
这怎么还不相信我了呢
I was telling the truth.
说几句实话
Can't you handle a few honest words?
怎么还听不下去了呢
Wait for me.
你等等我
[Think about it,]
你们想啊
[if our bank]
如果说我们银行
simply confronts
只是把企业
other businesses head-on
当成是对头
like they are the enemies,
来去硬刚的话
it'll only end in a lose-lose situation.
那结局只能是两败俱伤
Therefore, we need to find ways
所以我们要去想办法
to revitalize these companies
盘活企业
and help them regain the ability
让他们恢复
to generate revenue.
他们的造血能力
Only this way will it be a win-win
这样才能实现
for both the bank and the businesses.
真正的银企共赢
I've looked through
这些之前的
the previous loan contracts
民营企业的贷款合同
with the private companies.
我都已经看过了
Deferred repayment
无法按时还钱
is mainly because of
企业确实
the businesses.
有他们的问题存在
But the bank
不过我们银行
was not entirely faultless
在放款的时候
in the lending process.
也有我们的问题
[We were only focused on]
我们当时只想着
[giving out the loans quicker.]
赶紧把钱放出去
[We have never properly assessed]
根本就没有认真分析过
[the businesses' actual conditions]
企业的实际情况
[or their needs.]
和他们的贷款需求
The loan amount,
贷款的金额
duration,
期限
and repayment method
以及还款方式
were completely incompatible
跟企业的经营情况
with the businesses' conditions.
根本就不适配
Let's think out of box.
我们想这样的一个问题
If the businesses didn't receive
如果说在还款的时间里
desirable sales revenue
企业的销售回款
during the repayment period,
根本就没有到位
how could they
怎么可能
have repaid the bank?
给我们银行还钱
This is the real cause
这才是造成今天
of the situation we're in today.
这种局面的根本原因
Mr. Ji, we didn't really
纪总
think too much about it at the time.
当时我们也没想那么多
We only wanted to
就想着
give out the loans quicker
赶紧放出去
and get the job done.
把任务完成就行
I don't like to dwell on the past,
我这个人不喜欢翻旧账
but if these old issues
但如果说旧的问题
remain unresolved,
迟迟都没法解决
the Nan'an branch
咱们南安县支行
will never be able to
就永远不可能
bring in new clients
开拓出来新的客户
or meet the KPIs
也不可能完成总行
set by the headquarters.
给我们的关键绩效指标
I'm sure you don't want to
你们也不想
be stuck with just
每个月都只拿着
the base salary every month,
基础工资
always missing out
这绩效奖金
on performance bonuses,
是一分都捞不到
and still getting criticized
还得每天
by upper management every day, do you?
被上边领导批评吧
Of course not, Mr. Ji.
那肯定啊纪总
But it truly hasn't been easy
但这些年的日子
these years.
是真的不好过
[Mr. Ji,]
纪总
[what do you think]
您说
[we should do?]
咱们该怎么办
As long as we can meet
只要能完成
all the KPIs,
各项任务指标
we're willing to do whatever it takes.
您让我们干什么都行
The next two months
接下来的两个月
you'll need to work very hard.
可能会比较辛苦了
We'll need to be deeply involved
我们要扎根在
with each business,
每一家企业里
and get a though understanding of them.
对他们做更深入地了解
[If a business]
如果说这家企业
[is genuinely facing some problems]
真的有他们的问题
[and difficulties,]
有他们的困难
and if the owner is honest
负责人也踏踏实实
and willing to solve them,
想要做事的话
we'll work together
我们就和他们
with them to find
一起想办法
solutions for these non-performing loans.
解决这些不良贷款
What's the situation?
情况怎么样啊
Mr. Ji,
纪总
they said he went along
厂里人说他
with purchasing team to buy raw materials.
跟着驱车买原材料去了
I don't know if that's true though.
也不知道真的假的呀
[I just knew it.]
早就猜到了
[This Mr. Sun]
这个孙厂长
is the toughest case
是行里几笔不良贷款里
among the several bad loans the bank has.
最难啃的骨头了
And he always acts like
还整天一副
he's not afraid of anything.
天不怕地不怕的态度
It's like 'I don't have any money,
要钱没有
but take my factory if you want'.
要厂一个
Whether we sue or auction,
随便我们
he doesn't care.
是起诉还是拍卖
Yeah.
就是啊
Initially when we came here,
原本我们来的时候啊
he was at least respectful.
他还毕恭毕敬地
But in the end,
结果到后面
he didn't even bother to pretend anymore.
装都不装了
[He would]
直接
[simply hide]
我们来
[every time we come here.]
他就躲起来
[I have no words]
这个人
[for this person.]
不予评价了
If you ask me,
要我说呀
I don't think this Mr. Sun
这个孙厂长
is truly fearless.
还真不是天不怕地不怕
He must be convinced that
他一定是吃定了
we don't want this loan
我们不想让这笔贷款
to become non-performing
这么快就进入到
this soon.
不良处置程序
Think about it,
你想啊
if a newly issued loan become
如果说新发的贷款
non-performing within the same year,
当年就进入不良
our entire branch's performance
那咱们整个支行的绩效
will be ruined.
可就没了
So the best solution now
所以现在最好的办法
is to wait for him
就是等到他
and negotiate to him.
跟他协商处理
We'll trade the space
用时间
with time.
来换取空间
Mr. Ji,
纪总
I think it's going to rain soon.
我看这天也要下雨了
We still have time anyway.
反正咱还有点时间
Why don't we go home,
要不咱回去
[and come back tomorrow?]
明天再来也行啊
[Yeah, Mr. Ji.]
是啊纪总
We still have a week.
反正还有一周的时间
Let's come back tomorrow.
咱们明天再来吧
Okay then.
那这样吧
Since it's going to rain soon,
既然快下雨了
you guys go back,
你们先回
I'll wait a bit longer.
我再等一会儿
It's late now.
都已经这个时间了
The kids must be home from school.
孩子都放学了
Go home
赶紧回家
and make dinner for them now.
给他们做饭去
Thank you.
谢谢啊
[This Mr. Sun]
这孙厂长
[really is something.]
简直就不是个东西
Hello, Xiaoning.
喂 筱柠
I'm still not done here.
我这边还没忙完
I probably won't make it back tonight.
估计今天晚上回不去了
And the weather isn't good.
我看这天也不好
It's about to rain.
马上要下雨了
You should go to your parents' tonight,
你今天就去爸妈家吧
or I'll worry about you.
不然我不放心你
[Okay.]
好吧
[You be careful too.]
那你自己当心
[Do you have your overnight bag?]
过夜礼包在身边吧
Of course.
当然
It's in my car.
在车里呢
Don't worry.
放心吧
[Be careful.]
那你注意安全
[Bye bye.]
拜拜
Have some of this.
来点这个
It's raining heavily,
这又是
and it's getting colder.
暴雨又是降温的
Yuheng is away all alone,
这小纪一个人在外面
won't he get sick?
不会感冒吧
He's a man.
男人嘛
Some wind and rain
吹点风
is nothing.
强壮体格
It'll only make him
淋点雨
stronger.
锻炼心智
[Yuheng is mature and responsible.]
小纪稳重又有担当
Don't worry,
不用担心
he will surely take care of himself.
他肯定会照顾好自己的
Are you hearing what you're saying?
你说得这好听啊
Why don't you go outside
那你怎么不出去
and stay in the rain for a while
淋个个把小时
and see if it
也磨炼一下
makes you stronger.
坚强的心志呢
I'm too old for that.
我这把老骨头就算了
If I
我要是
do
是吧
get sick,
折腾病了
then
这
you two
你俩
will suffer as well.
不是跟着受累吗
[But to be honest,]
不过说实话
I really think Yuheng
我觉得小纪
is a good man.
这孩子真不错
Your dad and I are very happy with him.
我跟你爸都特别满意
Right?
是不是
I was really worried
就你俩这关系
about you
没曝光之前吧
before your relationship was made public.
我真担心
what it would do to your job.
你这工作受影响
I was so anxious everyday
那时候我天天焦虑
that I couldn't sleep.
我都睡不着
But I didn't dare to tell you.
但我不敢跟你说呀
I didn't want to bother you.
我怕你嫌烦
It wouldn't.
不会
It's true.
可不吗
When
就你俩的事
your relationship was made public,
被人知道的那会儿啊
your mom looked calm
你妈面子上看着
on the surface,
挺淡定的
but in reality,
可实际上啊
she was this close to be
差点进
sent to the ICU.
重症监护室了都
Can't you wish me something better?
你盼我点好事行不行啊
But fortunately,
不过幸亏呀
they only found out
曝光的就是你俩的
about your relationship,
恋爱关系
no one knew you've already registered.
没人知道你俩领证了
[If you knew that]
你们要是知道
[we're not really registered yet,]
我俩真的还没领证
[you wouldn't react this way.]
就不是现在的态度了
[I think Yuheng is truly a reliable man.]
但我觉得小纪真是靠谱
Look at how he was willing to
你看他为了
be transferred to a little town
保住你的工作
to protect your job.
宁愿自己调到县城里去
[As parents,]
我们当父母的
If we knew someone could
要是知道有人能
take care of our daughter
这么全心全意地
this wholeheartedly,
照顾咱们女儿
all of our worries
所有的担心啊
would vanish.
都烟消云散了
To be honest,
说真的
Mom,
妈
before
我以前
I only thought that
就只觉得
we liked each other
我们两个互相喜欢
and loved each other.
互相爱着对方
But,
但是
it was only through this thing that
通过这件事情我才知道
I realized I not only love him,
我不止爱他
but he is also truly someone
他也是真的值得我
I can spend my whole life with.
托付终身的人
[In the future,]
以后
[no matter what happens,]
不管遇到什么事吧
as long as we're together,
只要我们俩一起
we can solve anything,
肯定就都能解决
just like you two have.
像你们老两口一样
Our daughter is all grown up.
我们的女儿长大了
Hearing this,
我怎么
why am I
突然听了
suddenly a bit sad?
觉得有点挺伤感的呢
Enough,
行了
save your tears
你那眼泪啊
for the wedding.
留着婚礼上流吧啊
[Right,]
对呀
how's it going with your wedding?
你们这婚礼怎么着了
[You've registered for almost a year now.]
不是这领证都大半年了
Before, it was because it might affect
以前是为了怕耽误工作
your work. So now,
那现在
can I finally get my hopes up?
是不是我能有点盼头了
We're truly a bit busy.
确实有点忙
We don't have the time.
没时间
[He's just been transferred.]
他刚调到县里嘛
Besides
那除了
working and sleeping,
上班跟睡觉的时间
he spends all his time on the road.
都用在路上通勤了
He doesn't have the energy.
没这个精力
We'll wait a bit more.
再等等 再等等
When can he be transferred back
他在那个县城里
from that little town?
什么时候他能调回来呀
It must be exhausting going back and forth.
要不来回折腾多累得慌
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
对 对 对
This problem will be solved
反正问题呢
sooner or later.
迟早都会解决
It's only a matter of time.
就是看时间
I'll let you know
等解决好了
when it's solved.
再跟你们俩说
It just occurs to me that
我突然想起来
I have some more work to do.
我得加个班处理点事
You go ahead and rest.
你们俩早点睡啊
[Take this tea.]
拿着这茶
[Let me pour you some more.]
我再给你添点
I'm good, I'm good.
不用 不用 不用
Running away again from this topic.
一说这个就跑
He doesn't even have time to propose,
求婚都没时间
let alone a wedding.
还办婚礼
[You're still up]
这么晚了
[at this hour?]
怎么还没睡啊
Yeah.
没有呀
Such a beautiful night, of course
这么美好的夜晚
I'll be spending it working overtime.
当然要用来加班啦
[Looks like]
涂经理
[Miss Tu is very busy.]
看起来还挺忙
Aren't you busy as well?
你不也一样吗
[It's mostly because Jing]
主要是因为静姐
[is three month pregnant now]
她怀孕三个多月
[and suffers a lot from morning sickness.]
现在孕反得厉害
[On top of that, this is a crucial period]
正好呢又赶上
[for her promotion to general manager.]
她转总经理的关键期
[At least two major projects are needed]
至少要需要两个大项目
[to back it up.]
来做背书的
[So, of course I must offer a hand]
那小涂我肯定要帮帮忙
[and find more clients.]
多找一点客户了
Then perfect,
那正好
I also have a report to finish.
我呢也得赶一个报告
Let's work together then.
那咱俩一起呗
We'll keep each other company.
我们互相陪伴
Don't just look at me.
别光偷看我
Focus.
认真一点
How would you know that I'm looking at you
你不看我怎么知道
if you're not looking at me?
我看你啊
Are you asleep?
睡着了
Tu Xiaoning?
涂筱柠
[Are you really asleep?]
真睡着了
Sleep tight.
好好睡吧
Good night.
晚安
[Come over, everyone!]
大家都过来啦
We need to unload these raw materials!
卸原料啦
Okay.
好
Quickly, quickly, quickly!
快点 快点 快点
[Quickly, quickly!]
快点 快点
[Keep up!]
后面跟上
Let's do our best!
咱努努力加把劲
They will be useless if they get wet.
这些原料受潮就废了
Mister,
大爷
what are you unloading?
这卸什么呢
[Raw materials for food processing.]
都是食品加工原料啊
Mister,
大爷
are you Mr. Sun?
您是孙厂长吗
How could I
我可没有孙厂长
be the great Mr. Sun!
那么大的本事
That's Mr. Sun.
那才是孙厂长呢
He knew that my shoulder's injured
他知道我肩膀受伤啊
and took my place.
把我给替换下来了
[Let's work harder, everyone!]
大家再加把劲
If we sell this batch of food products,
这批食品加工卖出去了
everyone
下个月
will get their salary next month!
大家都有工资领了
[C'mon!]
加油
Here.
来
Wipe if off.
先擦擦吧
Take a seat.
坐 坐 坐
Okay.
好
There's no other clothes in the factory.
厂里没衣服了
You'll have to make do with
就现在的工服
this work uniform.
凑合着穿吧
Okay,
行
thank you.
谢谢啊
No problem.
没事
Mr. Sun,
孙厂长
let me introduce myself
我呢也给您
to you.
自我介绍一下
I am the new manager
我是咱们代瑞银行
at the Nan'an branch
南安县支行
of Dairui Bank.
新过来的经理
My name is Ji Yuheng,
我叫纪昱恒
you can call me Yuheng.
您可以叫我小纪
[I'm here today]
我今天过来啊
to learn more about
还是想了解一下
the loan and repayment situations
咱们银行贷款还款
here.
那些情况
As long as this factory is in my hands,
只要这个厂还在我手里
I'll keep it running.
我就一定会干下去
If
如果
the bank must take it away,
你们银行要收走
I have no choice
那我就只能
but to retire and go back to my hometown.
回家养老了
But I have no money
但要还款
to pay back the debts now.
我现在没钱
Mr. Sun, clam down.
孙厂长您先别着急
My colleague
您的想法
had already informed me about
还有您之前的一些意思
what you think
我的同事之前
and some of your ideas.
都已经转达给我了
This is the first time that we meet.
咱们今天是第一次见
The way you conduct yourself
您的为人处世
is truly very different
确实跟我预想的
from what I expected.
不大一样
I also spoke with
刚才我跟厂里
the senior staff at the factory
那些老员工啊
just now.
也都了解了一下情况
They all support you very much,
他们可都支持你
saying that
说您是
you're in this debt
被我们银行给骗了
because you were trapped by the bank.
所以才欠了这么多钱
I just want to
我呢就是想
know about
具体了解一下
what the situation was
当时的情况
exactly at the time.
到底是什么样子
Actually,
其实吧
it's not the bank's fault.
这个也不能怪银行
I was mostly to blame.
主要还是怪我自己
[Back then,]
当年
[I was focused on expanding the factory]
我一心想把工厂做大
[and helping everyone have a better life.]
带着大家一起发家致富
At the time,
当时
many banks came to me
有好多家银行找上门来
and offered me a loan.
要给我贷款
[I thought that was a good thing.]
我心想这是好事情啊
[So,]
所以
[I said yes]
也就
[to all of them.]
都应下了
We built new plants,
新建厂房
added more production lines.
增加生产线
[However,]
谁知道
[while production increased,]
产量倒是上去了
sales did not.
销量却没上去
It was a large stock,
一大批货呀
all stuck in inventory and unsold.
全压在手里卖不出去
[The cash flow]
现金流
has also dried up.
也断了
I couldn't
银行贷款
repay the bank loans,
也没法还
let alone having the money
更没有钱
to expand
去拓展渠道
some new sales channels.
打开销路了
I have an idea.
我倒是有一个办法
I don't know if
不知道您愿不愿意
you're willing to try it.
试一下
Hello, Mr. Liu.
喂 刘经理
Are you still up?
还没休息吧
[Mr. Ji, you're still up.]
纪总还没睡呢
[Do you want to go grab a drink?]
要不要出来喝一杯
Thanks,
谢谢啊
I'm good.
不用了
It's a bit late today.
今天太晚了
There's something I want to ask you.
有个事我还是想问问你
Can I
我找你
pick up the car
订的那辆车
I ordered from you this week?
这周可以提了吗
[I think so.]
应该差不多
[I'll let you know when it gets here.]
这两天车到了我通知你
Okay,
好
sure.
行
Thank you
那麻烦你了
for going through all that trouble.
多费心
[No problem.]
没事 没事
[It's nothing.]
小事
[Then I'll hang up then.]
挂了啊
Okay.
好
Thank you.
谢谢啊
[Xiaoning,]
筱柠
[when I'm not around, let this]
我不在身边的时候
[protect you from the wind and rain]
暂时让它帮你遮风挡雨
[and take you anywhere you want to go]
随时带你
[whenever you want.]
去想去的地方吧